Guide to the Mark Feeney Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Mark Feeney papers
1991-1991
MS 1698
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.34
The papers consist of an interview with Yale professor, C. Vann Woodward, conducted by Mark Feeney in preparation for his feature article, "Dean of American History." The papers also include interviews with former students and colleagues of Woodward.
Feeney, Mark
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mark Feeney, 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Biographical / Historical
Mark Feeney was born on July 28, 1957 in Winchester, Massachusetts. He received a B.A. from Harvard University in 1979. Upon graduation, he joined the staff of the Boston Globe and worked as an assistant book editor (1982), editor of the Focus section (1991), book editor and staff writer (1993-1994), and staff reporter (1995-).
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of an interview with Yale professor, C. Vann Woodward, conducted by Mark Feeney in preparation for his feature article, "Dean of American History." The papers also include interviews with former students and colleagues of Woodward.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic.
History -- Research; Brooks, Cleanth, 1906-1994; Feeney, Mark; Fields, Barbara Jeanne; Franklin, John Hope, 1915-2009; McFeely, William S.; McPherson, James M., 1936-; Woodward, C. Vann (Comer Vann), 1908-1999; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of History
- Original accession, 1991; Accession 1993-M-072
  - "Dean of American History," by Mark Feeney [photocopy of feature article on C. Vann Woodward], 1991 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Partial transcript of interview with C. Vann Woodward...", 1991 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Feeney interviews [audiocassettes]
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Interview with C. Vann Woodward (part 1), 1991 July 24; 1 (Box 2)
    - Interview with C. Vann Woodward (part 2), 1991 July 24; 1 (Box 3)
    - Interview with C. Vann Woodward (part 3), 1991 July 24; 1 (Box 4)
    - Interview with C. Vann Woodward (part 4), 1991 July 24; 1 (Box 5)
    - Interview with John Hope Franklin, 1991 August 5; 1 (Box 6)
    - Interview with James M. McPherson, 1991 August 6-7; 1 (Box 7)
    - Interviews with Cleanth Brooks, Barbara Fields, and William McFeely, [1991]; 1 (Box 8)